Guide to the Belmont Family Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Rothschild, Julie von Rothschild (Baroness Adolph von), 1830-1907 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Laura Thérèse von Rothschild (MrsJames Edouard de), 1847-1931 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Leopold de, 1845-1917 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Lionel de, 1808-1879 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Lionel Walter Rothschild, 2nd Baron, 1868-1937 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron) Louis Nathaniel von, 1882-1955 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Louise Montefiore de, Lady, 1821-1910 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Maria Perugia (Mrs Leopold de), 1862-1937 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron) Maurice Charles de, 1881-1957 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, May er Amschel de, I818-I874 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, Nathaniel May er Rothschild, 1st Baron, 1840-1915 (Box C)
  - Rothschild, (Baron)..Robert Philippe, 1880-1916 (Box C)
  - Rothschild & Sons Ltd, N.M. (London) (Box C)
  - Rothschild Frères, Messieurs de (Paris) (Box C)
  - Rothstein, Arnold, 1883-1928 (Box C)
  - Ryan, Thomas Fortune, 1851-1928 (Box C)
  - St Davids, (Sir) John Wynford Philipps, 1st Viscount, 1860-1938 (Box C)
  - St Roman, Marie Rosine Slidell, Countess de (Box C)
  - Samson, James Camille (Box C)
  - Sanger, Joseph Prentice, 1840-1926 (Box C)
  - Schiff, Jacob Henry, 1847-1920 (Box C)
  - Schuyler, Harriet Lowndes Langdon (Mrs. Philip) (Box C)
  - Schuyler, Louisa Lee, 1837-1926 (Box C)
  - Schuyler, Philip, 1836-1906 (Box C)
  - Schwab, Gustav Henry, 1851-1912 (Box C)
  - Scott, Francis Markoe, 1848-1922 (Box C)
  - Sedgwick, Robert (Box C)
  - Severance, Mark Sibley, 1846- (Box C)
  - Seward, Clarence Armstrong, 1828-1897 (Box C)
  - Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872 (Box C)
  - Seymour, Horatio, 1810-1886 (Box C)
  - Sherman, James Schoolcraft, 1855-1912 (Box C)
  - Sherman, John, 1823-1900 (Box C)
  - Sherwood, Arthur Murray (Box C)
  - Shields, George Oliver, 1846-1925 (Box C)
  - Shipman, William D. (Box C)
  - Sickels, Daniel Edgar, 1825-1914 (Box C)
  - Sinclair, Harry Ford, 1876-1956 (Box C)
  - Slidell, Ann C. (Box C)
  - Slidell, John, 1793-1871 (Box C)
  - Slidell, Thomas (Box C)
  - Smith, Hamilton, 1840-1900 (Box C)
  - Smith, Isaac T. (Box C)
  - Smith, John Amber, 1847-1892 (Box C)
  - Smith, John Cotton, 1826-1882 (Box C)
  - Smith, Milton H., 1836-1921 (Box C)
  - Smith, Thomas Kilby, 1820-1887 (Box C)
  - Speed, Keats, 1879-1952 (Box C)
  - Speyer, Ellin L. Prince Lowery (Mrs. James) (Box C)
  - Speyer, James, 1861-1941 (Box C)
  - Speyer, Wolfgang (Box C)
  - Spreckels, Adolph Bernard, 1857-192U (Box C)
  - Stanchfield, John Barry, 1855-1921 (Box C)
  - Stanley, August us Owsley, 1867-1958 (Box C)
  - Stephany, S. S. (Box C)
  - Stetson, Francis Lynde, 1846-1920 (Box C)
  - Stevenson, Paul Eve, 1868-1910 (Box C)
  - Stimson, Henry Lewis, 1867-1950 (Box C)
  - Stonehouse, J. B. (Box C)
  - Storey, Wilbur Fisk, 1819-1884 (Box C)
  - Straight, Willard Dickerman, 1880-1918 (Box C)
  - Straus, Oscar Solomon, 1850-1926 (Box C)
  - Stull, Henry, 1851-1913 (Box C)
  - Sullivan, James Edward, 1860-1914 (Box C)
  - Summers, James Colling, 1854-1929 (Box C)
  - Sumner, Charles Allen, 1835-1903 (Box C)
  - Sutro, Theodore, 1845-1927 (Box C)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1882-1958 (Box C)
  - Taft, Henry Waters, 1859-1943 (Box C13)
  - Takamine, Jokichi, 1854-1922 & Caroline Hitch Takamine (Box C13)
  - Taylor, Bayard, 1825-1878 (Box C13)
  - Taylor, Henry Clay, 1845-1904 (Box C13)
  - Tennant, John Hunter, 1869-1933 (Box C13)
  - Terry, Charles Appleton, 1858-1939 (Box C13)
  - Thayer, William Greenough, 1863- (Box C13)
  - Thomas, John Wilson (Box C13)
  - Thompson, Robert Means, 1849-1930 (Box C13)
  - Thompson, Will L., 1847-1909 (Box C13)
  - Thomson, Frank, 1841-1899 (Box C13)
  - Tiffany, Isabella Bolton Perry (Mrs. George), 1834-1912 (Box C13)
  - Tiffany, Jane Caroline Perry (Box C13)
  - Tiffany, Perry (Box C13)
  - Tilden, Samuel Jones, 1814-1886 (Box C13)
  - Tower, Louise G. Dreer (Mrs. August us Clifford) (Box C13)
  - Townsend, Isaac (Box C13)
  - Townsend, Robert (Box C13)
  - Tracy, Benjamin Franklin, 1830-1915 (Box C13)
  - Trimble, Lawrence Strother, 1825-1904 (Box C13)
  - Turenne d'Aynac, Gabriel Louis, Comte de, 1843-1907 (Box C13)
  - Untermyer, Samuel, 1858-1940 (Box C13)
  - Van Buren, John, 1810-1866 (Box C13)
  - Van Buren, William Holme, 1819-1883 (Box C13)
  - Vanderbilt, Cornelius, 1843-1899 (Box C13)
  - Vanderbilt, Cornelius, 1873-1942 (Box C13)
  - Vanderbilt, Grace Graham Wilson (Mrs. Cornelius), 1870-1953 (Box C13)
  - Vanderbilt, William Kissam, 1849-1920 (Box C13)
  - Vanderpoel, Aaron J. and others (Box C13)
  - Wadsworth, James Wolcott, 1877-1952 (Box C13)
  - Walker, Duncan S. (Box C13)
  - Walker, Leroy Pope, 1817-1884 (Box C13)
  - Wallace, William Andrew, 1827-1896 (Box C13)
  - Walsh, Michael (Box C13)
  - Ward, Samuel, 1814-1884 (Box C13)
  - Warden, William (Box C13)
  - Wardman, Ervin, 1848-1923 (Box C13)
  - Warren, Whitney,-1943 (Box C13)
  - Waterbury, John Isaac, 1850-1929 (Box C13)
  - Watson, J. Herbert (Box C13)
  - Weatherby, Edward (Box C13)
  - Webb, William Seward, 1851-1926 (Box C13)
  - Webster, Hamilton Fish (Box C13)
  - Webster, Sidney, 1828-1910 (Box C13)
  - Weller, August us N. (Box C13)
  - Westbury, Richard Lutrell Pilkington Bethell, 3rd Baron, 1852-1930 (Box C13)
  - Westervelt, Jacob Aaron, 1800-1879 and others (Box C13)
  - Westinghouse, George, 1846-1914 (Box C13)
  - Wetmore, Edith Malvina Keteltas (Mrs. George P.) (Box C13)
  - Wetmore, Edmund,-1918 (Box C13)
  - Wharton, Edith Newbold Jones, 1862-1937 (Box C13)
  - Whiting, Sarah Swan (Mrs. August us L.) (Box C13)
  - Whitman, Charles Seymour (Box C13)
  - Whitney, Caspar W., 1862-1929 (Box C13)
  - Whitney, Harry Payne, 1872-1930 (Box C13)
  - Whitney, William Collins, 1841-1904 (Box C13)
  - Wicker, Cassius Milton, 1846-1913 (Box C13)
  - Wickersham, George Woodward, 1858-1936 (Box C13)
  - Wiley, Louis, 1869-1935 (Box C13)
  - Williams, John Sharp, 1854-1932 (Box C13)
  - Williams, John Skelton, 1865-1926 (Box C13)
  - Wilson, George, 1839-1908 (Box C13)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924 (Box C13)
  - Winthrop, Henry Rogers, 1876-1958 (Box C13)
  - Winthrop, Robert Charles, 1809-1894 (Box C13)
  - Wise, John Sergeant, 1846-1913 (Box C13)
  - Wolcott, Frances M. (Box C13)
  - Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927 (Box C13)
  - Woods, James Haughton, 1864-1935 (Box C13)
  - Woodward, George Washington, 1809-1875 (Box C13)
  - Woodward, James T.,-1910 (Box C13)
  - Zuylen van Nyevelt, Elise, Baroness van (Box C13)
- Series II: Uncataloged Papers
  - 1799-1875 (Box 1)
  - 1876-1890 (Box 2)
  - 1891
    - A-G (Box 3)
    - H-O (Box 4)
    - P-W (Box 5)
    - Z, and paid bills (Box 6)
  - 1892-1905 (Box 7)
  - 1906-1907 (Box 8)
  - 1908-1909 (Box 9)
  - 1910-1911A (Box 10)
  - 1911B-1912A (Box 11)
  - 1912B (Box 12)
  - 1913 (Box 13)
  - 1914A (Box 14)
  - 1914B-1915 (Box 15)
  - 1916-1917 (Box 16)
  - 1918-1920 (Box 17)
  - 1921 (Box 18)
  - 1922-1923A (Box 19)
  - 1923B-1924A (Box 20)
  - 1924B-1929 (Box 21)
  - Belmont Family Tree (Box 21)
  - Photographs (Box 21)
- Series III: Letterbooks
  - No. 8, 1863-1865 (Box 22)
    (Correspondence with the Rothschilds and others)
  - 1866-1916 (Box 22)
    (Loose pages cut from letterbooks)
  - 1882-1886 (Box 22)
    ("Private")
  - "Confidential"--Mostly financial correspondence with the Rothschilds
    - No. 1, 1891 January -1894 April (Box 23)
    - No. 2, 1894 April -1898 April (Box 23)
    - No. 3, 1898 June -1904 February (Box 23)
    - [No. 4], 1904 March-May (Box 23)
    - No. 4[a], 1904 May-1910 February (Box 23)
    - No. 5, 1910 February-1915 February (Box 24)
    - No. 6, 1915 March-1922 August (Box 24)
    - No. 7, 1922 September -1925 March (Box 24)
    - [No. 8] "A.B. & Co.", 1892 January -1924 December (Box 24)
  - "Private Letters"--Correspondence about horses, yachting, finance, and personal matters
    - No. 16, 1891 February-April (Box 25)
    - No. 17, 1891 April -June (Box 25)
    - No. 18, 1891 June -September (Box 25)
    - No. 19, 1891 September -November (Box 25)
    - No. 20, 1891 November -1892 January (Box 26)
    - No. 21, 1892 January -March (Box 26)
    - No. 22, 1892 March-June (Box 26)
    - No. 23, 1892 June -September (Box 26)
    - No. 24, 1892 September -1893 January (Box 27)
    - No. 27 1893 June -October (Box 27)
    - No. 37, 1895 July -October (Box 27)
    - No. 38, 1895 October -1896 January (Box 27)
    - No. 39, 1896 January -March (Box 28)
    - No. 40, 1896 March-May (Box 28)
    - No. 41, 1896 May -October (Box 28)
    - No. 42, 1896 October -1897 January (Box 28)
    - No. 43, 1897 January -April (Box 29)
    - No. 44, 1897 April -June (Box 29)
    - No. 45, 1897 June -September (Box 29)
    - No. 46, 1897 September -December (Box 29)
    - No. 47, 1897 December -1898 February (Box 30)
    - No. 48, 1898 February-April (Box 30)
    - No. 72, 1903 January -April (Box 30)
    - No. 73, 1903 April -June (Box 30)
    - No. 74, 1903 June -August (Box 31)
    - No. 75, 1903 September -November (Box 31)
    - No. 76, 1903 November -1904 January (Box 31)
    - No. 77, 1904 January -April (Box 31)
    - No. 78, 1904 April -July (Box 32)
    - No. 79, 1904 July -October (Box 32)
    - No. 80, 1904 October -December (Box 32)
    - No. 81, 1904 December -1905 February (Box 32)
    - No. 82, 1905 February-April (Box 33)
    - [No. 83], 1905 April -June (Box 33)
    - No. 84, 1905 June -July (Box 33)
    - No. 88, 1906 February-April (Box 33)
    - No. 92, 1906 November -1907 January (Box 34)
    - No. 93, 1907 January -March (Box 34)
    - No. 94, 1907 March-May (Box 34)
    - No. 95, 1907 May -July (Box 34)
    - No. 96, 1907 July -October (Box 35)
    - No. 97, 1907 October -December (Box 35)
    - No. 102, 1908 October -1909 January (Box 35)
    - No. 103, 1909 January -February (Box 35)
    - No. 111, 1910 February-April (Box 36)
    - No. 113, 1910 June -August (Box 36)
    - No. 114, 1910 August -October (Box 36)
    - No. 115, 1910 October -December (Box 36)
    - No. 116, 1910 December -1911 January (Box 37)
    - No. 117, 1911 January -March (Box 37)
    - No. 118, 1911 March-April (Box 37)
    - No. 124, 1912 February-March (Box 37)
    - No. 125, 1912 March-May (Box 38)
    - No. 126, 1912 May -June (Box 38)
    - No. 127, 1912 June -September (Box 38)
    - No. 128, 1912 September -November (Box 38)
    - No. 129, 1912 November -1913 January (Box 39)
    - No. 130, 1913 January -February (Box 39)
    - No. 131, 1913 February-April (Box 39)
    - No. 132, 1913 April -June (Box 39)
    - No. 133, 1913 June -September (Box 40)
    - No. 134, 1913 September -November (Box 40)
    - No. 135, 1913 November -1914 January (Box 40)
    - No. 136, 1914 January -March (Box 40)
    - No. 137, 1914 March-April (Box 41)
    - No. 138, 1914 April -June (Box 41)
    - No. 139, 1914 June -August (Box 41)
    - No. 140, 1914 August -November (Box 41)
    - No. 141, 1914 November -1915 January (Box 42)
    - No. 142, 1915 January -March (Box 42)
    - No. 143, 1915 March-May (Box 42)
    - No. 144, 1915 May -July (Box 42)
    - No. 145, 1915 July -October (Box 43)
    - No. 146, 1915 October -December (Box 43)
    - No. 147, 1915 December -1916 February (Box 43)
    - No. 148, 1916 February-May (Box 43)
    - No. 149, 1916 May -July (Box 44)
    - No. 151, 1916 September -December (Box 44)
    - No. 152, 1916 December -1917 February (Box 44)
    - No. 153, 1917 February-April (Box 44)
    - No. 154, 1917 April -June (Box 45)
    - No. 155, 1917 June -September (Box 45)
    - No. 156, 1917 September -November (Box 45)
    - No. 157, 1917 November -1918 April (Box 45)
    - No. 158, 1918 April -June (Box 46)
    - No. 159, 1918 June -October (Box 46)
    - No. 160, 1918 October -1919 March (Box 46)
    - No. 161, 1919 March-August (Box 46)
    - No. 162, 1919 August -November (Box 47)
    - No. 163, 1919 November -1920 February (Box 47)
    - No. 164, 1920 February-May (Box 47)
    - No. 165, 1920 May -October (Box 47)
    - No. 166, 1920 October -1921 January (Box 48)
    - No. 167 1921 January -April (Box 48)
    - No. 168, 1921 April -July (Box 48)
    - No. 169, 1921 July -October (Box 48)
    - No. 170, 1921 October -1922 January (Box 49)
    - No. 171, 1922 January -May (Box 49)
    - No. 172, 1922 May -August (Box 49)
    - No. 173, 1922 August -November (Box 49)
    - No. 174, 1922 September -1923 March (Box 50)
    - No. 175, 1923 March-August (Box 50)
    - No. 176, 1923 July -November (Box 50)
    - No. 177, 1923 November -1924 February (Box 50)
    - No. 178, 1924 February (Box 51)
    - No. 179, 1924 June -November (Box 51)
    - No. 180, 1924 November -1925 February (Box 51)